# **Theresa Hoffmann**

# User Experience Researcher

Pittsburgh, PA | theresahoffmann.ux@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/theresahoffmann | behance.net/theresahoffmann

UX Researcher with a background in English literature and PR. Skilled in user research and testing, including surveying, interviewing, and usability testing. Experienced in translating research findings into actionable insights.

### **PROJECTS**

### HandCrafted, UX/UI Designer & Researcher

May 2022

Create an e-commerce site that makes web3 accessible to everyone. Within 6 days, conducted a user survey, secondary
research, and competitor analysis to assess problem space, then designed, tested, and revised a prototype. Successfully
submitted the finished product and a presentation thereof to the judges of the Avocademy Designathon.

# PlantPeople, UX/UI Designer & Researcher

November 2021-June 2022

Build an app that connects hobby gardeners with plant experts for tips and advice. Cycled the project through User-Centered
Design Process from Discovery to Prototype and Test, serving as lead researcher and designer over the course of the project.
Created a clickable prototype ready for hand-off to developers.

## **SKILLS & TOOLS**

User-Centered Design Methodology, User Research, User Personas, User Flows, Card Sorting, Information Architecture, Wireframing, Prototyping, UI Design, UX Writing, Usability Testing, App Design, Web Design, Agile Methodology, Oral and Written Communication

Adobe XD, Illustrator, InDesign, Photoshop, Figma, Balsamiq, Marvel, LucidChart, Optimal Workshop, Survey Monkey, MS Office, Google Workspace, Dropbox, HTML5, CSS3, FigJam, Miro, Trello, Notion

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# **UX Research Apprentice**, Tech Fleet

May 2022-Present

• Increase user engagement for The Serious Type, a social platform for teens to share creative work. Conducted a competitor analysis, user interviews, user surveys, secondary research, and multiple card sorts to understand the problem space and better meet users wants and needs. Designed a progressive web app to replace the current The Serious Type website.

**Account Executive**, RW Jones Agency

March 2019-May 2021

Account Coordinator, Dick Jones Communications/RW Jones Agency

June 2016-March 2019

**Leasing Agent, Alvern Gardens Apartments, Prudential Realty Company** 

August 2013-May 2016

Freelance Writer, University of Pittsburgh at Bradford Communications & Marketing

June 2013-August 2013

#### **EDUCATION**

CareerFoundry User Experience Design Certificate (Expected August 2022)

Intensive project-based online training program with a focus on user experience design, user research, user interface design, and frontend development.

Duquesne University, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania (May 2016)

Master of Arts in English Literature with a Concentration in Writing and Media Technology

Cook Honors College (CHC) at Indiana University of Pennsylvania (IUP), Indiana, Pennsylvania

Bachelor of Arts in English Writing and Film Studies, summa cum laude